cookielaw.org 2019-05-10

# Our Privacy Policy | The Cookie Collective

We are committed to protecting your information and respecting your privacy rights. The aim of this page is to explain how we may gather and use information about you through your interactions with us, including use of this website and other software developed by us.  All use of such information is governed by the principles and practices set out in this statement.  

**Key Points:**

  * Any personal information you give us via forms on the site is treated as confidential and only used to provide our services or communicate with you about them.
  * We only share your information with third parties acting on our behalf to provide our services, or where required by law.
  * By sending us information via a form on this site, you consent to our use of this information as explained on this page.
  * Your use of this site implies consent for the setting of cookies, unless you change your privacy preferences. For more information on the cookies we use see: How We Use Cookies

**Last Update** : 18 Aug. 2014

Who We Are

**Optanon** is a registered trademark of [Governor Technology](http://www.governor.co.uk/ "Governor Technology"). For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is Governor Technology Ltd of 133 Creek Road, London, SE3 8BU, United Kingdom.

Information we may collect from you 

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Contact details that you provide by filling in forms on this site. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our services, posting material or requesting further services.
  * If you contact us, we will keep a record of our correspondence.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of your orders.

Uses made of the information

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to login or participate in interactive features of our online services, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

We may also use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we may contact you about these by email or telephone.

Email Newsletters

If we send you an email newsletter to the address supplied by you, it will contain tracking images that enable us to see when you open the email. We will also know if you click on any link contained in the email.

We use this information to help us improve the quality and relevance of our communications. If you do not download images in our emails, then we are not able to track when you open or read the emails we send.

You can unsubscribe from any newsletters at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the email sent.  If you do this we will not send you any more newsletters, however we will keep your details on file in order to be able to comply with this promise.

Optanon Auditor Data Collection

The Optanon Auditor and its associated plug-in for Google Chrome gathers data about cookies and submits it to our database.

This data contains information both about the cookies found, and the pages on a particular site they were found on.  It also contains values of cookies, which in some circumstances may contain personally identifiable information - if the cookie is designed to hold such information.  Such information is only ever used to help us identify the purpose of a cookie, where a website owner has requested this service from us.  The data is only available to us and our clients who use the auditor for specific websites.

We do not use any personally identifiable information for any other purpose, and nor do we make it available in any other way.

All submissions of data via the Optanon Auditor are otherwise completely anonymous.  If using the plug-in, no information is collected about the device the plug-in is installed on, or the person using the device.  No browsing history, other than a record pf pages that set cookies, is complied, and no profile linked to a device can be created from the data.

The names and some attributes of the cookies gathered by the auditor are made publicly available on the [Cookiepedia](http://cookiepedia.co.uk/ "Cookiepedia") website.  However there is to our knowledge no personal information contained within this data.

Privacy Detective Cookiepedia Plug-in 

Aside from the Optanon Auditor, our [Privacy Detective](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/cookiepedia-privacy-detec/oicbhgcaoofklplaiijhkkcmflkenmij "Privacy Detective") plug-in for Google Chrome submits data about cookies to our systems.  This is done automatically, without any kind of user input or control. 

The data consists of the names of cookies and their other attributes, along with the top level domain name of the site being visited by the browser, when the data was submitted.  The values (contents) of the cookies are not stored, nor the specific pages of the site they were found on.  We do not identify the source of the data submitted back to a particular copy of the plug-in. We therefore believe that no personal data is collected by the Privacy Detective.

The sole purpose of the plug-in is to source data about cookies to inform our research.  Statistics and other intelligence garnered from analysis of this data are published freely on [Cookiepedia](http://cookiepedia.co.uk/ "Cookiepedia - all about cookies").

Prior to this plug-in there were two Cookie Collector plug-ins, for Firefox and Chrome available.  Data collection from these plug-ins is no longer taking place.

Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for one of our suppliers.

By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * If Governor Technology or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use or terms and conditions of supply and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Governor Technology, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. 

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to info@cookielaw.org

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

Links to Other Websites

We may from time to time publish links to other websites we believe to be of interest. However we have no control over these sites, which are not governed by this privacy policy. 

Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to info@cookielaw.org
